Guide to the James Weldon Johnson and Grace Nail Johnson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1896-1972; Series I; 18.14; (46 boxes)
  - James Weldon Johnson Correspondence, 1896-1972
    - Carter, Edward C. (Edward Clark)
      See: Institute of Pacific Relations, Box 10, folder 229
    - Carter, Elmer Anderson, 1931-37, undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
      To: 10 / From: 7
    - Carter, Herman J.D., 1932-35, undated (Box 5, Folder 84)
      To: 9 / From: 2
    - Carter, William D., 1936, undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
      To: 3 / From: 2
    - Casely-Hayford, Gladys, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - "Ce-Ch" General (Box 5, Folder 87)
      To: 31 / From: 26
    - Century Magazine, 1906-22 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Chase National Bank of the City of New York, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Chesnutt, Charles W. (Charles Waddell), 1913-32, undated (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Childers, James Saxon, 1935-37, undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
      To: 8 / From: 3
    - Church, Robert R., 1937-38 (Box 5, Folder 92)
      To: 0 / From: 3
    - "Ci-Com" General (Box 5, Folder 93)
      To: 41 / From: 25
    - Clark, Evans
      See: Twentieth Century Fund, Box 14, folder 346
    - Clement, Rufus E., 1933, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Clinchy, Everett R.
      See: National Conference of Christians and Jews, Box 14, folder 346
    - Cobb, James A. (James Adlai), 1916-29 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1929, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      To: 4 / From: 4
    - Cole, Bob, undated (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Coles, L.F., 1931-34 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - "Con-Cq" General (Box 5, Folder 99)
      To: 42 / From: 15
    - Connelly, Marc, [1930], 1932 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Consular Letters
      Correspondence Johnson received while in Puerto Cabello (Venezuela) and Corinto (Nicaragua) regarding consular duties and life
      - "A-O" General, 1908-13 (Box 5, Folder 101)
        To: 10 / From: 0
      - "P-Z" General and unidentified, 1908-13 (Box 5, Folder 102)
        To: 14 / From: 0
    - Cook, Mercer, 1937-38 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Courtney, Augusta, 1926-37, undated (Box 5, Folder 105)
      To: 28 / From: 4
    - Covarrubias, Miguel, undated (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - "Cr-Cz" General (Box 6, Folder 107)
      To: 39 / From: 16
    - Crosby, Emily, 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Cullen, Countee, 1925-34 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      To: 18 / From: 4
    - Cunard, Nancy, 1931-32, undated (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Cuney, Waring, 1934-37 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      To: 11 / From: 0
    - "Da-Dd" General (Box 6, Folder 112)
      To: 34 / From: 16
    - Daniel, A. Mercer, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Dabney, Wendell P., 1930-35 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      To: 6 / From: 2
    - Darrow, Clarence, 1921-33, undated (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Darrow, Ruby, 1927-38, undated (Box 6, Folder 116)
      To: 9 / From: 1
    - Davis, Jackson, 1933-34 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Davis, Harry E., 1933, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Dawson, William L., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "De-Dh" General (Box 6, Folder 120)
      To: 33 / From: 27
    - Delany, Hubert T., 1929-36 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Delta Phi Delta, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 122)
      To: 6 / From: 9
    - DeSuze, Carl, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Dett, R. Nathaniel, 1929, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - "Di-Dg" General (Box 6, Folder 125)
      To: 32 / From: 19
    - Dillard, James H., 1937 (Box 6, Folder 126)
      To: 2 / From: 1
    - "Do-Dz" General (Box 6, Folder 127)
      To: 28 / From: 16
    - Dodd, Mead and Company, 1913, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Dodson, Owen, 1932-33 (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Donahoe, Edward, 1932, 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 130)
      To: 7 / From: 1
    - Doubleday and Company Inc., 1916-37 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Douglas, Aaron, 1927-37 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Drake, J.F., 1934-35 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Dreiser, Theodore, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - DuBois, Rachel Davis, 1932-36 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1914-30 (Box 6, Folder 136)
      Includes: Villard, Oswald Garrison 1/0 letters (copy) with William E.B. DuBois 1915 Mar 31
      To: 20 / From: 2
    - Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1931-38, undated (Box 6, Folder 137)
      To: 34 / From: 12
    - Dunbar, Paul Laurence, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Frank M. Hopkins
      To: 0 / From: 1 letter (copy) with
    - "Ea-Ek" General (Box 7, Folder 139)
      To: 20 / From: 9
    - Eastman, Max, 1928-33, undated (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Eddy, Sherwood, 1929-36 (Box 7, Folder 141)
      To: 7 / From: 6
    - "El-Ez" General (Box 7, Folder 142)
      To: 26 / From: 19
    - Eleazer, R.B., 1931-37 (Box 7, Folder 143)
      To: 11 / From: 5
    - Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers)
      See: Julius Rosenwald Fund, Box 17, folder 414
    - Ernst, Morris Leopold, 1930-37 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - "Fa-Fk" General (Box 7, Folder 145)
      To: 43 / From: 21
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1921, 1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Fisher, Rudolph, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - "Fl-Fq" General (Box 7, Folder 150)
      To: 43 / From: 24
    - Fortune, Timothy Thomas, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Foster, William, 1929, undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
      To: 6 / From: 4
    - Fountain, William A., 1938 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - "Fr-Fz" General (Box 7, Folder 154)
      To: 21 / From: 13
    - Francis, Nellie F., 1932-35 (Box 7, Folder 155)
      To: 10 / From: 4
    - Franklin, Claire, undated (Box 7, Folder 156)
      Includes letter from Franklin to Mrs. Van Vechten
      To: 0 / From: 1
    - Franklin, John Hope, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Frazier, Edward Franklin, 1932, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Frohlich, Richard F.
      See: ASCAP, Box 2, folder 17
    - "Ga-Gk" General (Box 7, Folder 159)
      To: 50 / From: 28
    - Gale, Zona, 1927-35 (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Gallager, Buell G., 1934-37 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Gannett, Lewis, 1932-36, undated (Box 7, Folder 162)
      To: 12 / From: 4
    - Garden, Mary, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Garland Fund
      See: American Fund for Public Service, Box 1, folder 14
    - Gates, Dorothy, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 164)
      original JWJ letter To: 0 / From: 1
    - Gilbert, Ethel Bedient, 1932-33 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      Includes: Parrish, Lydia A. 1/1 letters (copies) with Ethel Bedient Gilbert 1932 Jul 19, Jul 27
    - "Gl-Gq" General (Box 8, Folder 166)
      To: 28 / From: 13
    - Gordon, Asa H., 1936-37 (Box 8, Folder 167)
      Includes: Martin, Eugene M. 1/0 letters with Asa H. Gordon 1936 Nov 28
      To: 7 / From: 5
    - Gould, Mirian N., 1934 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - "Gr-Gz" General (Box 8, Folder 169)
    - Granger, Lester B. (Lester Blackwell), 1936 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Graves, Anna M., 1933 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Graves, William C., 1919-27 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Green, Paul, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - Gregory, Montgomery, 1916-37 (Box 8, Folder 174)
      To: 4 / From: 1
    - Grimké, Francis J. (Francis James), 1929 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Gruening, Ernest H., 1921 (Box 8, Folder 176)
      To: 0 / From: 2
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1932-37 (Box 8, Folder 177)
      To: 11 / From: 6
    - "Ha-Haq" General (Box 8, Folder 178)
      To: 20 / From: 12
    - Hackley, E. Azalia (Emma Azalia), 1915 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Haiti
      - "A-H" General, 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 180)
        Correspondence with Haitians regarding U.S. occupation of Haiti and JWJ's articles on Haiti
        To: 15 / From: 8
      - "L-T" General and unidentified, 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 181)
        To: 6 / From: 3
      - Berthomieu Denache, 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 182)
      - J. Jolibois fils
        See: Joblis fils, J., Box 11, folder 236 To: 5 / From: 1
        To: 5 / From: 1
      - Jean Price-Mars, 1920, undated (Box 8, Folder 183)
      - Chrysostome Rosemond, 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 184)
      - H. Pauléus Sannon, 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 185)
        To: 5 / From: 9
      - Georges Sylvaine, 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 186)
        To: 11 / From: 11
      - Miscellaneous items, c. 1920-22 (Box 8, Folder 187)
        Includes: DuBois, W.E.B. 1/0 letters with J.C. Bailey 1920 Mar 19
        Includes ALS from J.C. Baily to W.E.B. Du Bois 1920 Mar 19
    - Halstead, A., 1914, undated (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Hamilton, John D., 1938 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), 1922-38 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - "Har-Hd" General (Box 9, Folder 191)
      To: 34 / From: 14
    - Harcourt Brace & Company, 1921-30 (Box 9, Folder 192)
      Includes: Brown, Sterling 1/0 letters (copy) with Charles A. Pearce of Harcourt, Brace and Co. 1931 Dec 11
      Includes: Spingarn, Joel E. 6/3 letters 1921 Sep 30 - 1925 Dec 2
      To: 31 / From: 34
    - Harcourt Brace & Company, 1931-71 (Box 9, Folder 193)
      To: 46 / From: 23
    - Hare, Maud Cuney, 1915, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 194)
    - Harmon Awards, 1929-30 (Box 9, Folder 195)
      To: 10 / From: 1
    - Harper & Brothers, 1927-38 (Box 9, Folder 196)
      To: 15 / From: 4
    - Harrison, Hubert H., 1915 (Box 9, Folder 197)
    - Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - Hayes, Roland, 1923-27 (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - Haynes, George Edmund, 1916-29 (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Haynes, Mrs. George Edmund (Olyve L. Jeter), 1938 (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1930-31 (Box 9, Folder 202)
    - "He-Hl" General (Box 9, Folder 203)
      To: 34 / From: 17
    - Hershaw, L.M., 1929 (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Heyward, DuBose, 1925, [1931] (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - Hikida, Yasuichi, 1933-36 (Box 9, Folder 206)
    - Hill, Leslie Pinckney, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - Hills, J. Seth, 1930-36 (Box 9, Folder 208)
    - "Ho-Ht" General (Box 9, Folder 209)
      To: 64 / From: 44
    - Holly, Alonzo P., 1929 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - Holmes, Dwight Oliver Wendell, 1934, undated (Box 9, Folder 211)
    - Holmes, John Haynes, 1925-34 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - Hope, John, 1916-35 (Box 9, Folder 213)
      To: 24 / From: 10
    - Horne, Frank S., 1930-34 (Box 9, Folder 214)
    - Howe, Arthur, 1933, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 215)
      Includes correspondence with Margaret A. Howe
    - Howe, Marie Jenney, 1917, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 216)
    - "Hu-Hz" General (Box 10, Folder 217)
      To: 19 / From: 10
    - Hughes, Charles Evans (secretary), 1916 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1930-36, undated (Box 10, Folder 219)
      To: 10 / From: 2
    - Hunt, Frances Marietta, 1932-38, undated (Box 10, Folder 220)
      To: 8 / From: 6
    - Hunt, Henry A., 1916, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - Hurst, Fannie, [1927], 1931, undated (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - Hurston, Zora Neale, 1934, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - Huyck, Laura Talmage, 1932-37, undated (Box 10, Folder 224)
      To: 43 / From: 3
    - "Ia-Iz" General (Box 10, Folder 225)
      To: 23 / From: 15
    - Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1932 (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Imes, G. Lake (George Lake), 1927, n.y. (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Imes, Nella L.
      See: Larsen, Nella
    - Imes, William Lloyd, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations
      - General, 1929-37 (Box 10, Folder 229)
        Includes: Spingarn, Arthur B. 1/1 letters (copies) with Edward C. Carter 1929 Aug. 14
        Includes correspondence re: Kyoto Conference
        To: 28 / From: 10
      - General, 1929-37 (Box 10, Folder 230)
        Addresses, reports, lists, etc.
      - Edward C. Carter, 1929-33, undated (Box 10, Folder 231)
        To: 32 / From: 8
    - International House, 1932-37 (Box 10, Folder 232)
      Chicago and New York
    - "Ja-Jn" General (Box 11, Folder 233)
      To: 27 / From: 20
    - Jackson, George Pullen, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - Jackson, Juanita E.
      See: Mitchell, Mrs. Clarence M., Box 14, folder 327
      See: Baltimore City-Wide Young Peoples' Forum, Box 3, folder 35
    - Jeter, Olyve L.
      See: Haynes, Mrs. George Edmund, Box 9, folder 200
    - "Joa-Jom" General (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - Joblis, fils J., 1921-35 (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - Johnson, Charles S., 1925-37 (Box 11, Folder 237)
      Includes correspondence with Marie B. Johnson
      To: 32 / From: 6
    - Johnson, Deacon, 1916, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - Johnson, Georgia Douglas Camp, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 239)
    - Johnson, Guy Benton, 1931-35 (Box 11, Folder 240)
    - Johnson, James P., undated (Box 11, Folder 241)
    - James Weldon Johnson Clubs, 1933-38 (Box 11, Folder 242)
      Correspondence with clubs named in JWJ's honor
    - James Weldon Johnson Dinner 1906 (Box 11, Folder 243)
      Minutes and letters of the banquet committee, Colored Republican Club, New York
    - James Weldon Johnson Dinner 1931 (Box 11, Folder 244)
      Letters received by the committee
    - James Weldon Johnson Dinner 1931 (Box 11, Folder 245)
      Letters received by the committee from N.A.A.C.P. Branches
    - James Weldon Johnson Literary Guild, 1932-38, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 246)
      To: 16 / From: 2
    - Johnson, Mordecai W. (Mordecai Wyatt), 1929-35 (Box 11, Folder 247)
    - Jolson, Al, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 248)
    - "Jon-Jz" General (Box 11, Folder 249)
      To: 24 / From: 11
    - Jones, David D., 1927-34 (Box 11, Folder 250)
      To: 6 / From: 5
    - Jones, Eugene Kinckle, 1916, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - Jones, Joshua Henry, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 252)
      To: 1 / From: 3
    - Jones, Sissiertta, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 253)
    - Jones, Thomas E., 1931-32 (Box 11, Folder 254)
      To: 18 / From: 7
    - Jones, Thomas E., 1933-35 (Box 11, Folder 255)
      Includes: Hurston, Zora Neale 0/1 letters (copy) with Thomas E. Jones 1934 Oct 12
    - Jones, Thomas E., 1936-39 (Box 11, Folder 256)
      Includes: Stribling, T.S. 0/1 letters (copy) with Thomas E. Jones 1937 Aug
      To: 36 / From: 12
    - Jones, Thomas J., 1932 (Box 11, Folder 257)
    - Jones, William N., 1935 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    - Juger, Esther, 1930, 1931, undated (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund
      See: Julius Rosenwald Fund
    - "Ka-Kl" General (Box 12, Folder 260)
      To: 45 / From: 18
    - Kern, Jerome D., 1916 (Box 12, Folder 261)
    - Kilby, Lemuel, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - "Kn-Kz" General (Box 12, Folder 263)
      To: 13 / From: 9
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1925-37, undated (Box 12, Folder 264)
      To: 28 / From: 7
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1927-1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 265)
      To: 60 / From: 15
    - Knopf, Alfred A. Jr. ("Pat"), undated (Box 12, Folder 266)
    - Knopf, Blanche W., 1925-30 (Box 12, Folder 267)
      To: 39 / From: 13
    - Knopf, Blanche W., 1931-37 (Box 12, Folder 268)
      To: 26 / From: 10
    - Knox, John, 1932-37 (Box 12, Folder 269)
    - Knox, P.C., 1911 (Box 12, Folder 270)
    - Koening, Samuel S., 1928 (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - Kuhn, Hedwig S., 1933-38, undated (Box 12, Folder 272)
      To: 13 / From: 4
    - "La-Ld" General (Box 12, Folder 273)
      To: 21 / From: 22
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    - LaFarge, John, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 275)
    - LaFarge, Oliver, 1933-34 (Box 12, Folder 276)
    - LaFollette, Fola, 1931, undated (Box 12, Folder 277)
      Includes letter from George Middleton
      To: 7 / From: 0
    - La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1931, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 278)
    - Lambert, Constant, 1931, undated (Box 12, Folder 279)
    - Lampkin, Daisy E. (Daisy Elizabeth), 1933, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 280)
    - Lardner, Ring, 1925, undated (Box 12, Folder 281)
    - Larsen, Nella, 1933-35, undated (Box 12, Folder 282)
      Includes: Peterson, Dorothy 0/3 letters to James Weldon Johnson, addressed jointly with Nella Larsen 1933 Oct 4 - 1935 Feb 27
    - Latimer, Ira H., 1932-33 (Box 12, Folder 283)
      To: 3 / From: 5
    - "Le-Lh" General (Box 12, Folder 284)
      To: 38 / From: 29
    - League of American Writers, 1937-38 (Box 12, Folder 285)
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 286)
    - L'Engle, E.J., 1914-25 (Box 12, Folder 287)
      To: 37 / From: 23
    - Leonard, H.H., 1911-13 (Box 12, Folder 288)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1922-37 (Box 12, Folder 289)
      New York Times, New York Tribune, The New Yorker
      To: 0 / From: 5
    - Lewis, Morris, 1934-35 (Box 12, Folder 290)
    - Lewis, Sinclair, 1929, undated (Box 12, Folder 291)
    - "Li-Ll" General (Box 13, Folder 292)
    - Lieberson, Goddard, 1932-34, undated (Box 13, Folder 293)
      To: 9 / From: 4
    - Lindsay, Vachel, 1925, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 294)
    - Livingston, Lemuel W., 1916, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 295)
      To: 1 / From: 2
    - "Lo-Lz" General (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - Locke, Alain LeRoy, 1934-37 (Box 13, Folder 297)
    - The London Times, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 298)
      To: 1 / From: 4
    - Logan, James T., 1929-34 (Box 13, Folder 299)
      To: 13 / From: 10
    - Logan, Rayford Whittingham, 1936-37 (Box 13, Folder 300)
    - Lomax, John A., 1937 (Box 13, Folder 301)
    - Long, Arthur T., 1930, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 302)
    - "Ma-MacC" General (Box 13, Folder 303)
      To: 25 / From: 19
    - Mabry, Tom, 1932-34 (Box 13, Folder 304)
      Includes: Jones, Thomas E. 1/0 letters (copy) with Tom Mabry 1933 Apr 19
      To: 21 / From: 4
    - McConnell, Fanny M., 1931-38 (Box 13, Folder 305)
      To: 30 / From: 0
    - McCormick, Mendill, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 306)
    - "MacD-Macy" General (Box 13, Folder 307)
      To: 25 / From: 21
    - McKay, Claude, 1928-1935 May (Box 13, Folder 308)
      To: 27 / From: 14
    - McKay, Claude, 1935 Jul-1938 (Box 13, Folder 309)
      To: 32 / From: 7
    - "Mad-Maz" General (Box 13, Folder 310)
      To: 49 / From: 23
    - Marinoff, Fania
      See: Van Vechten, Carl, Box 21, folder 497
    - Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1928-37 (Box 13, Folder 311)
      Includes: Wright, R. R. 0/1 letters (copy) with Edward B. Marks Music Co. 1931 Apr 21
      To: 17 / From: 15
    - Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1939-72, undated (Box 13, Folder 312)
      To: 18 / From: 2
    - Martin, Eugene M., 1936 (Box 13, Folder 313)
    - Martin, Isadore Maximilian, 1930-34 (Box 13, Folder 314)
      To: 5 / From: 6
    - Matthews, Brander, 1908-25 (Box 13, Folder 315)
      Includes: Roosevelt, Theodore (son of President Roosevelt) 0/1 letters with Brander Matthews 1918 Apr 17
      Includes: Root, Elihu 0/1 letters with Brander Matthews 1913 Feb 21
    - Matthews, William B., 1929, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 316)
    - Mays, Benjamin E. (Benjamin Elijah), 1937 (Box 13, Folder 317)
    - "Mb-Mh" General (Box 14, Folder 318)
      To: 16 / From: 5
    - The Meeting Place, 1929-33 (Box 14, Folder 319)
    - Mencken, Henry Louis, 1916-37 (Box 14, Folder 320)
      To: 54 / From: 8
    - Meyer, Annie Nathan, 1931-34, undated (Box 14, Folder 321)
      To: 13 / From: 6
    - "Mi-Ml" General (Box 14, Folder 322)
      To: 36 / From: 14
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1930-37, undated (Box 14, Folder 323)
    - Miller, Kelly, 1916, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 324)
    - Miller, Lucile V., 1929-38, undated (Box 14, Folder 325)
      To: 7 / From: 3
    - Correspondence re: Florence Mills, 1927, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 326)
    - Mitchell, Mrs. Clarence M. (Juanita Jackson), 1937 (Box 14, Folder 327)
    - "Mo-Mz" General (Box 14, Folder 328)
      To: 48 / From: 22
    - Monroe, Harriet, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 329)
    - Moore, Alfred D., 1931-36 (Box 14, Folder 330)
      To: 15 / From: 11
    - Moore, Fred R. (Frederick Randolph), 1914-16 (Box 14, Folder 331)
      Includes: Terrell, Robert H. 0/1 letters with Fred R. Moore 1914 Dec 21
      To: 8 / From: 0
    - Moorland, Jesse Edward, 1922, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 332)
    - William Morrow & Company, 1933, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 333)
    - Moryck, Brenda Ray, 1927-37, undated (Box 14, Folder 334)
      To: 13 / From: 1
    - Moton, Robert Russa, 1915-32 (Box 14, Folder 335)
      To: 14 / From: 3
    - Muir, Lewis F., 1915, undated (Box 14, Folder 336)
    - Murphy, Carl J., 1922, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 337)
    - Muse, Clarence, 1935-36 (Box 14, Folder 338)
    - "Na-Nd" General (Box 14, Folder 339)
      To: 27 / From: 10
    - Napier, James Carroll, 1932-35 (Box 14, Folder 340)
      Includes: Johnson, Mordecai W. 0/1 letters with James C. Napier 1932 Feb 27
    - Nash, Roy, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 341)
    - Nashville International Club, 1932-33 (Box 14, Folder 342)
      includes agenda and draft constitution To: 5 / From: 0
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.) - National Office, 1921-35 (Box 14, Folder 343)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.) - Local Branches, 1916-38, undated (Box 14, Folder 344)
      To: 16 / From: 8
    - National Association of Colored Graduate Nurses, 1916, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 345)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1931-38 (Box 14, Folder 346)
      Includes correspondence with Everett Clinchy
    - National Folk Festival 1934, 1934, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 347)
      Includes: Hurston, Zora Neale 0/1 letters (copy) with Sarah Gertrude Knott 1938 Jan 26
      St. Louis, Mo.
      To: 13 / From: 11
    - National Movement for the Establishment of a Forty-ninth State, 1934-35 (Box 14, Folder 348)
    - "Ne-Nz" General (Box 15, Folder 349)
      To: 45 / From: 32
    - Nerney, May Child, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 350)
    - Negro Actors Guild of America, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 351)
    - Nelson, Alice Dunbar, 1917, 1922, undated (Box 15, Folder 352)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1932, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 353)
      To: 16 / From: 7
    - New York University, 1934-38 (Box 15, Folder 354)
      Correspondence re: courses
      To: 21 / From: 7
    - Norman, Dora Cole, 1926, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 355)
      Sister of Bob Cole
    - "Oa-Oz" General (Box 15, Folder 356)
      To: 26 / From: 15
    - Odum, Howard Washington, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 357)
    - Okala, Ollie Jewell Sims, 1934-38 (Box 15, Folder 358)
    - Open Forum Speakers Bureau, 1931-37 (Box 15, Folder 359)
      To: 43 / From: 30
    - Ovington, Mary White, 1919-38, undated (Box 15, Folder 360)
      Includes: Reddick, Lawrence D. 0/1 letters (copy) with Mary White Ovington 1936 Dec 23
      To: 22 / From: 6
    - Oxford Council on Church, State and Society 1937, 1936-37 (Box 15, Folder 361)
      To: 20 / From: 8
    - "Pa-Pd" General (Box 15, Folder 362)
      To: 20 / From: 10
    - Page, Kirby, 1929-36 (Box 15, Folder 363)
    - Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1920-36 (Box 15, Folder 364)
    - Parsons, Herbert E., 1916, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 365)
    - Payne, E. George (Enoch George), 1934-38, undated (Box 15, Folder 366)
      Includes original JWJ letters
      To: 23 / From: 19
    - "Pe-Pg" General (Box 15, Folder 367)
      To: 28 / From: 19
    - Peabody, George Foster, 1918-32 (Box 15, Folder 368)
    - Peacock, Roscoe, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 369)
    - Pearce, Charles A.
      See: Harcourt, Brace and Co., Box 9, folder 192
    - Pelham, Robert A., 1915, undated (Box 15, Folder 370)
    - Periquet y Zuaznabar, Fernando, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 371)
    - Peterkin, Julia Mood, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 372)
    - Peterson, Dorothy, 1922-33 (Box 15, Folder 373)
    - "Ph-Pl" General (Box 16, Folder 374)
      To: 27 / From: 7
    - Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, 1930-38 (Box 16, Folder 375)
      To: 21 / From: 19
    - Pickens, William, 1916-33 (Box 16, Folder 376)
      Includes: DuBois, W.E.B. 1/0 letters (copy) with William Pickens 1931 Apr 4
      Includes: White, Walter 1/0 letters (copy) with William Pickens 1931 May 6
      To: 19 / From: 8
    - Pickens, William, 1934-37 (Box 16, Folder 377)
      Includes: Ovington, Mary White 3/1 letters (copies) with William Pickens 1931 Apr 30 - May 5